ANIL KUMAR PANDIYA





+91 9672598162



SOCIAL



🌪 PROFILE

anilpandiya.github.io linkedin.com/in/anilpandiya github.com/Anilpandiya

I am a professional Software Engineer, Having 7+ years of technical experience in IT. Proficient in developing Single Page Apps using React Ecosystem. As a developer worked in all phases of project life cycles. Strong learning curve in adapting quickly to emerging technologies.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer Pregin Jun 2020 - present

- Building FinTech product Pregin Pro & Pregin Cura apps
- Preqin Pro is being developed using React ecosystem and used Rest APIs as backend architecture to access the Mongo database.
- Pregin Cura is developed on Micro frontend architecture.
- Developed ESG components for both apps.
- Working on a custom UI components library for internal use.
- Handle deployment and release process for the project.

Software Engineer iBASEt

Apr 2019 - Jun 2020

- Developed Solumina Product for Lockheed Martin, Air Bus
- Added reusable components and published them as npm packages.
- Build a native mobile app Unit info for android and ios.
- · Contributed in post-production activities such as Defect Fixing, Performance Tuning and Framework Upgradation.

Senior Analyst Capgemini Jul 2017 - Apr 2019

- · Application is being developed using Angular 6 framework and used Rest APIs as backend architecture to access the Oracle database.
- Developed many CR's as well for different regions based on specific requirements and worked on maintaining versions.
- Planned new designs and functionality and developed modules.
- Contributed on existing application Security Management System's enhancements
- Prepared MD50 and knowledge management documents.



Intern

IBM, Jaipur

May 2016 - Jun 2017

EXPERTISE

React & React native Next JS, Angular JavaScript, TypeScript Webpack, Rspack RTL, Jest, Enzyme HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap Material UI, SASS Redux, Redux-Saga RxJS, Axios, Lodash



OTHER SKILLS

Micro Frontend Architecture GraphQL, Node JS REST APIs, Websocket Ionic, Expo AWS IAM, CI/CD Team City, Zipkin MySQL, Mongo DB StackBlitz, FireBase Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket



EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology CSE SKIT M&G, Jaipur 74.03% 2013 - 2017.

Senior Secondary GSSS, Bhilwara 2012. 70.06%